Georgy Buranov

Georgy Buranov CV

About me

Brief

- Full name : Georgy Buranov
- Job title : Senior Software Developer
- Area of interest: Accepting interesting Ruby on Rails, Go and C++ offers
- Homepage: http://gburanov.me
- LinkedIn profile : http://www.linkedin.com/in/gburanov
- Stackoverflow profile: https://careers.stackoverflow.com/cv/edit/270418
- Github profile: https://github.com/gburanov

Contact information

- Country: Germany
- Address : Sewanstraße 5, 10319 Berlin
- Birthdate: 22.08.1981
- Nationality: Russian. Got German working permit
- Open for reallocation: Yes (if the offer is REALLY interesting)
- Phone: +49 1523 663 2480

Summary

I worked as a C++ software developer for a very long time, but now I decided to switch to web backend (currently Ruby/ROR)

I still beleive in compiled & static typed languages, so I see future in languages like Go/Skala.

More than 11 years of commercial software development for Europe or US established companies. Working for both software (Quest Software, Acronis, Avira, Wimdu) and non-software (Reuters) companies. Working for both companies

that create their own solutions (Acronis, Quest Software, Avira, Wimdu) and outsource (Reuters).

Working experience in two countries with different cultures - Russia and Germany

Ability to work on all three main platforms, although at home I use Ubuntu as desktop OS and OSX as laptop OS.

Ability to create, understand and implement design specifications. Ability to solve complicated problems.

Ability to quickly understand new code and start contributing without significant delay.

Knowledge of agile methodologies.

Git advanced mode. Experience of using GIT in advanced mode (branches, merges, cherry-picking, etc). Understaing of github pull request process.

Good communicative skills. Every day communicating with English-speaking management.

Working with huge amount of legacy code.

Open-source experience (Chromium browser, GRUB2, etc...). Ability both to understand existing design and to contribute to the open-source (sometimes by finding golden middle)

Ability to work in team. Wide experience in using collaborative software; repositories, bug tracking systems, review systems.

Ability to automate routine jobs.

Wide use of automated testing (unit tests, functional tests, integration tests, acceptance tests). Unit testing of legacy code.

Career History

Wimdu: Oct 2015 - Now

Senior Ruby Developer : Berlin, DE

- Mobile Api, Affiliate Api
- Supporting mobile API projects (fixing bugs, extending API)
- Affiliate API project start from scratch
- Docker/Puppet deploy
- Measuring statistics using Kibana

Knowledge:

- Getting familiar with AWS stack
- Trying to do micro-service approach
- Testing approaches for microservices

Freelance: May 2012 - Oct 2015

Backend Software developer, Team manager: Russia, Germany

Responsibilties:

- Working on projects backend alone from beginning to the very end
- Projects maintaining
- Details (as well as source code) are available upon request

Knowledge:

- Ruby
- Rails
- Automated Testing (rspec, capybara)
- Tons of gems

Avira: Nov 2014 - Oct 2015

Software Engineer, Browser Project: Tettnang, DE

- Browser based on Chromium
- Starting new project completely from scratch
- Creating project environment (build tools, scripts, documentation)

Knowledge:

- Working with really HUGE amount of legacy code
- Ability to inject your code in correct place in quite small amount of time
- Advanced GIT (merging to constantly developing open-source and back)

Avira: Sep 2013 - Nov 2014

Unix and Mac software developer: Tettnang, DE

Responsibilties:

- Avira Rescue System (Ubuntu based system for rescue booting and restoring your OS)
- OsX version of Avira products
- Responsible for maintaining (and writing new code) for kernel extension (driver)

Knowledge:

- Agile software development approach
- Legacy code unit tests coverage
- New code unit test coverage
- Working with GIT

Acronis: Aug 2008 - May 2013

Software Developer, Senior Software Developer, UEFI project : Moscow, RUS

Responsibilties:

- Investigation of new booting mechanism (UEFI)
- Fix "Bootability restore" module for UEFI
- UEFI loader
- Understanding, documentation and coding of UEFI boot mechanism for both Windows and Linux
- Multiplatform solution

Acronis: Aug 2008 - May 2013

Software Developer, Senior Software Developer, Bootability detect/restore : Moscow, RUS

Responsibilties:

- Detecting/restoring different OSes bootability (different Linux versions, Windows)
- Bootability investigation (all levels, from MBR to kernel loading)
- refactoring + maintaining code
- Multiplatform solution

Acronis: Aug 2008 - May 2013

Software Developer, Senior Software Developer, Fdisk project : Moscow, RUS

- Fdisk library has about the same functionality as Linux fdisk. It is the base core library of all Acronis products
- Support + new functionality for fdisk library
- Code documentation

- Maintenance of LDM, MBR, GPT libraries
- Implementing Storage spaces support (new Windows 8/2012 feature)
- Multiplatform solution

-

Acronis: Aug 2008 - May 2013

Software Developer, Scheduler project: Moscow, RUS

Responsibilties:

- Multiplatform scheduling service for starting tasks (backups, verification, etc.) at special timepoint
- Multiplatform development&debugging (Windows, Linux, Mac)
- Module for task scheduling, based on cron (Linux), LauchAgent (Mac) and Windows Service (Windows)

Allied Testing: Jan 2007 - Sep 2008

Software Developer, Reuters project:

- Reuters got a huge platform for dealing with different finance aspects Reuters 3000 Xtra.
- We were responsible for Calculators plugin. It was calculating market values using predefined templates.
- Every day connecting to Paris office
- Huge amount of code supporting
- Working with bank software (more security and code check)
- Invention of unit testing (JUnit library)

Quest Software (now part of Dell): May 2005 - July 2006

Software Developer, Recovery Manager for Exchange:

Responsibilties:

- Designing Object-Oriented library for Jet Blue Engine.
- CRUD API for working with Exchange store (Read, Write, Update, Delete)
- Layer over the library for using with managed code.
- Reading messages from store without Exchange Server (No-SQL Jet Blue Database)

Knowledge:

• -Studying design patterns -OO libraries from scratch.

Axensis Moscow: Dec 2003 - May 2005

Software Developer, Auditor project, IIS collection module:

Responsibilties:

- Developing GUI using Qt
- DB Storage modification (SQL, C#)
- Integration with other modules using COM
- Collection IIS information
- Improvement of special language for collection (in short, C++ code generation language, based on XML, XSLT)

Knowledge:

- My first job as a software developer.
- Learning STL, Boost, Qt.
- Working with SVN, bug tracking system.

Logrus: Jul 2002 - August 2003

QA:

Responsibilties:

- Manual (70%) and Automated (30%) testing.
- Logrus was responsible for localization of huge software projects, like Microsoft Windows and Lotus Notes

Knowledge:

• Working for not full time in a big company I gained knowledge of different processes going on in big companies

MEPHI 26 department : Sep 2002 - Feb 2004

Software developer:

Responsibilties:

• Payment module for car detection system. It was used for some time on several car stations

Skills

Operation systems

Windows:

Wide experience (from Windows95 to Windows8) , Good knowledge of Booting mechanism , Good knowledge of disk management

Linux:

Wide knowledge (mostly Ubuntu, Fedora) , Good knowledge of Booting mechanism , gdb , Scripting (ability to automate tasks)

OSX:

Wide experience (from OSX 10.7), Writing kernel extensions experience

Collaboration tools

Repositories:

Git (including github) , SVN , CVS

Messengers:

Hipchat , Flowdock

Web-based repositories:

Github , Bitbucket

Bug tracking systems:

 $\operatorname{TrackIt}$, $\operatorname{Clarify}$, $\operatorname{Bugzilla}$, Jira , $\operatorname{Redmine}$

Code review systems:

 Code collaboraror , Github pull requests

Full stack solutions:

Atlassian stack (Jira, Bamboo, Stash, Confluence)

Programming Languages

Wide experience (more then 10 years):

C, C++ (including C++11)

Moderate experience (from 2 to 5 years):

Ruby (including Ruby on Rails) , Python

Learning now:

Rust, Go

Basic experience:

Java, C#, Javascript (including jQuery, AngularJS, React)

IDE:

Atom.io, Vim, Eclipse, RubyMine

Programming styles

OOP:

 $\mathrm{C}{++}$, $\mathrm{C}\#$, Java , Ruby , Good knowledge of design patterns

Functional programming:

C++ (templates), Haskell, Clojure (basics)

Dynamically typed languages:

Ruby, Javascript, Python

Web

Frameworks:

Wide use of Ruby on Rails

Microservices:

Separate deploys (docker), Communication channels, Small teams

OS stack technologies

Wide experience:

Win32API , Unicode , COM , ATL , Jet Blue Engine , Hard Drives Partitioning (GPT, MBR, LDM, LVM) , Windows Storage Spaces , Bootability (BIOS, UEFI, MBR, loading stages, GRUB, NTLDR, WBM)

Moderate experience:

Boost , Multi-threading , OSX kernel extensions

Testing tools Unit testing: jUnit , xUnit , NUnit , cppUnit , rspec Functional testing:

Languages

capybara

Languages

• Russian : Native

English: Upper Intermediate
German: Intermediate (B 2)
Spanish: Beginner (A2.1)

Language certificates

• English : IELTS certificate 7.0 total

Education

FMSH 2 (Physical and mathematical school) : Sep 1995 - Aug 1998 : Sergiev Posad, RUS

MEPHI (National Research Nuclear University) : Sep 1998 - May 2004

Master in Physics : Moscow, RUS

Additional Trainings
Allied Testing: Nov 2007 - Mar 2008
Financial math trainings: Moscow, RUS
Allied Testing: Apr 2008 - Sep 2008
Project Management trainings (Allied Testing) : Moscow, RUS
Online Berkeley course https://class.coursera.org/saas : Jan 2012 - Apr 2012
Software as a service (SAAS) : Online
Online Stanford course https://www.coursera.org/course/compilers: Oct 2012 - Dec 2012 Compilers.: Online
Online Stanford course https://class.coursera.org/gametheory-2012-002/class: Jan 2013 - Feb 2013 Game theory.: Online
Online Princeton course https://class.coursera.org/algs4partI-002/class: Feb 2013 - Mar 2013
Algorithms: Online

Online Princeton course https://class.coursera.org/algs4partII-001/class/index : Apr 2013 - May 2013
Algorithms part 2: Online
Axensis Moscow : Sep 2004 – May 2005 English courses (Upper Intermediate) : Moscow, RUS
Goethe institute, Moscow: Sep 2005 – Sep 2007
German courses (Intermediate) : Moscow, RUS
Avira : Sep 2013 - Now
German courses: Tettnang, DE
Cervantes institute, Moscow : Jan 2010 - Jan 2011
Spanish courses: Moscow, RUS
Private courses, Moscow : Jan 2012 - Jun 2012
Arabic courses: Moscow, RUS